Komail Dharsee

290 Demott Ln, Somerset, NJ, 08873

Objective

Modern security research often places hardware within the trusted computing base; however, the growing cost and complexity of fabrication infrastructure increases the difficulty of having trusted parties at all stages of manufacturing. The emerging resemblance of hardware design to software design bolsters my effort to mitigate vulnerabilities from hardware using software-oriented techniques.

Education

University of Rochester

PhD, Computer Science

2016-Present

Rutgers University

BS, Computer Science

2010-2014

Work Experience

University of Rochester

Research Assistant September 2016-Present

Applying formal methods and software-oriented approaches towards defenses against hardware vulnerabilities.

PNNL

Summer Intern March 2020–Present

Applying formal methods translate an ISA-based security policy to an equivalent policy described at the microarchitectural abstraction point

MIT Lincoln Laboratory

Summer Intern June 2018–August 2019

Analyzed hardware trojans detected by sophisticated hardware trojan detection mechanisms. Identified hardware trojan properties necessary to enable/evade detection. Designed trojans to enable/evade several trojan-detection mechanisms. Designed measures to evaluate detection mechanism reliability based off hardware properties.

Acquire Media

Software Engineer

June 2015-August 2016

Back-end engineer working on the feed handler team. Designed and wrote feed handlers which collect and clean raw feed (commonly received in xml or json) fetched from various web scrapers, ftp sources, and other feed delivery tools. Reviewed colleagues' feed handler implementations prior to release.

Microsoft

Microsoft Student Partner

September 2013-June 2014

Served as a Technical Evangelist for Microsoft at Rutgers University. Held App Development and Microsoft service training events. Lead and assisted students towards devloping and publishing apps for the Windows Store.

Rutgers University

Assistant Researcher

September 2012–December 2013

Explored the construction of a novel file system that includes new content paradigms hooked to MongoDB. Built a prototype FUSE user-level file system to allow a dual (shell and MongoDB) file-system interface. Explored the applications of Hadoop cluster programming utilizing the Map/Reduce framework towards indexing file systems for search focused application.

Publications

- o Dharsee, K., Johnson, E., and Criswell, J. (2017). A software solution for hardware vulnerabilities. In *2017 IEEE Cybersecurity Development (SecDev)*, pages 27–33
- o Johnson, E., Dharsee, K., and Criswell, J. (2019). Secure Guest Virtual Machine Support in Apparition. In *Proceedings of the 15th ACM SIGPLAN/SIGOPS International Conference on Virtual Execution Environments*, VEE 2019, pages 17–30, New York, NY, USA. ACM